# JOHN W TRENT

## SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Virtualization Architect with extensive experience in design and management of information technologies, documentation specialist of systems infrastructures, project deployment specialist of software implementations, instructor of systems training & orientation of Microsoft, Citrix and Vmware implementations. Certified in Citrix Technologies as a Citrix Certified Enterprise Administrator (CCEA), Microsoft Windows Servers and Exchange Server as Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE), Vmware Virtual Technologies as Vmware Certified Professional (VCP) Cisco Certified Unity Engineer. Proficient in communication skills and extensive customer support. Over 25 years experience in diverse, extensive, professional management of IT Delivery staffing & operations.

### **EDUCATION**

Vmware Advanced Management New Horizons Bellevue, Wa Vmware Certified Professional VCP 2003, 2004, 2005

 Certified in engineering, installing & deployment of GSX, ESX & Vmware Workstation

Citrix Advanced Administration Infotrain Costa Mesa, Ca Citrix Certified Administrator CCA 2000, 2002, 2004, 2005
Citrix Certified Enterprise Administrator CCEA 2003, 2004, 2005

 Certified in engineering, installing & deployment of Citrix Metaframe 1.8, Metaframe XPe, Citrix Secure Gateway, Citrix Infrastructure Assessment, Citrix Presentation Server 3.0

Microsoft Windows Training Accelerated 2K Training San Francisco, Ca Microsoft Certified Professional MCP 2000, 2002 Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer MCSE 2002

Microsoft Exchange Enginner 2003

- Certified in engineering, installing & deployment of Microsoft 2000 Server, Active Directory installation & administration, Microsoft Exchange 2000 deployment & administration
- Certified in Cisco Voice Unity Systems 2003

Microsoft NT4.0 Server Administrator Executrain Reno, Nv

Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer MCSE 1997

 Certified in engineering, installing & deployment of GSX, ESX & Vmware Workstation Cabrillo College Watsonville High School High School Graduate 1974 Aptos, Ca

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## February 2019 to present

Collabera

Citrix Architect/Engineering Consultant for Starbucks Coffee

Citrix Architect specializing in Virtual Desktops, Virtual Infrastructure, Xenapp Server and Application management, Supporting Starbucks Corporate & Retail Citrix Environments:

- VDI Implementation using Citrix Xendesktop & Xenapp 7.15
- Citrix Netscaler Infrastructure
- Data Center consolidation & Upgrade to 2016 & Windows10
- Upgrading from Xenapp 6 to 7.15 Farms
- Physical to Virtual Desktop migration

January 2011 to January 2019

Digestive Health Specialists

IT Architect/Engineer

Systems Architect specializing in Citrix, Microsoft & Unix Infrastructure, Vitual Desktops, Virtual Infrastructure, Network Infrastructure, Storage & Disaster Recovery. Providing expertise for Software projects including Nuance Dragon various roles as technical engineer, project manager and Citrix design specialist, including:

- VDI Implementation using Citrix Xendesktop & Xenapp 6.5 through 7.9
- Citrix XenServer virtual server expansion
- Citrix Netscaler Infrastructure
- Data Center consolidation & Disaster Recovery
- Physical to Virtual Desktop migration
- Network WAN design & deployment
- SAN configuration & maintenance

January 2006 to present

Starbucks Coffee Company

Lead Systems Engineer

Systems Architect specializing in Citrix Infrastructure & Secure Access Technologies providing expertise for Starbucks on projects since 2002 in various roles as team supervisor, technical engineer, project manager and Citrix design specialist, including:

Citrix Xenapps upgrade & migration

- Retail Citrix Expansion & 64bit server implementation
- EMEA Data Center migration and deployment
- Germany Citrix deployment to all Retail stores
- China Citrix Farm Design & Implementation
- Retail Citrix Farm POC for Store Portal implementation

May 2002 to December 2005

Right! Systems, Inc

Consultant for Starbucks Coffee Company

Systems Analyst specializing in Citrix Metaframe, providing expertise for Starbucks on projects since 2002 in various roles as technical engineer, project manager and Citrix design specialist, including:

- Citrix Metaframe XPe upgrade & migration from Starbucks 1.8 Farm
- Citrix External Access Design & Implementation
- UK Citrix Farm Design & Artisan Software Implementation
- China Citrix Farm Design & Implementation
- Retail Citrix Farm POC for Store Portal implementation
- Manugistics Upgrade Project
- Clients & Profits Upgrade Project
- CVDC Alternate Hosting Project
- Hear Music Project

January 2000 to December 2005

Right! Systems, Inc

Consultant for various companies & State Organizatons

Senior Systems Architect for HP, Microsoft, Citrix, Vmware & Cisco technology implementations

- Tommy Bahama, Seattle, Wa
- Attorney General, State of Washington
- Department of Transportation, State of Washington
- Digestive Health Specialists, Tacoma, Wa
- Seattle Seahawks, Seattle, Wa
- King County Library, Issaquah, Wa
- Banner Bank, Walla Walla, Wa
- County of Walla Walla, Walla Walla, Wa
- Thurston County, Olympia, Wa
- WSIPC, Everett, Wa
- Wells Fargo Escrow, Washington State

4/1999 to 12/1999

Infostream

Implementation Director/Help Desk Manager

- Design & Implementation Engineer to integrate & package Title & Escrow software into customer sites utilizing Microsoft & Citrix technologies
- Help Desk Support Manager

Managed team of 10 support engineers of first and second level support for software and Microsoft Systems for 450 customers

nationwide.

9/1997 to 4/1999

First American Title

State Manager of Information Systems

Managed First American Title of Nevada 's Information Systems and statewide IT staff from Reno to Las Vegas. Responsible for staffing, budgets, IT vision & implementation of new state office & branches across the state. Implemented first Windows/Citrix statewide deployment for First American Title & Escrow offices and Title Plant.

7/1994 to 9/1997

First American Title

Systems Engineer

Systems Engineer to migrate/integrate dissimilar Title/Escrow software systems into centralized deployment strategies & developing WAN for Regional Deployment of Novell Directory Services

8/1990 to 7/1994

First American Title

Title Operations Manager

Manager of Title production operations for Nevada County, California title plant. Supervisor of title personel, systems operation & production of Title Insurance Product. Developed 1st countywide database for recording documents in Sacramento Region

2/1980 to 8/1990

Chicago Title

Title Officer

Examination of Title Records & preparation of Legal Documents & Title Policies for Real Property

## REFERENCES

Susan Ross,	Former IT Director,	Digestive	Health Specialist	(253) 988-
9505			•	

Jason Maynard, Senior Engineer, Citrix (425) 260-7031

Doug Brown, Citrix Technology Expert (954) 778-9558

Ron Jenkins, Facilities Director, Seahawks (206)730-0907

Steve Bennett, Retired CIO, First American Title (775)831-9218

Matthew Anderson, Nimble Senior Engineer (425)939-2813